fitchburgstate.edu 2019-09-09

# 

Website Privacy Policy
This privacy policy governs your use of Fitchburg State websites (“Sites”) and mobile
applications (“Mobile Apps”), created by Fitchburg State University.
This document informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure
of Personal Information we receive from users of our Sites and Mobile Apps.
What We Collect
Fitchburg State collects two kinds of information on its Sites and Mobile Apps:
1) User Provided Information
This is information you voluntarily supply when you visit the Sites and Mobile Apps, such as
when you:
     • Register an account;
     • Fill out a form to request information;
     • Apply for admissions or request services;
     • “Opt-in” for participation in a service;
     • Complete a survey;
     • Engage with other site features.
2) Automatically Collected Information
This is non-personal information that is collected automatically as you navigate the Sites and
Mobile Apps, such as:
    • The name of the domain and host from which you access the Web;
    • The geographic location of your point of connectivity;
    • The Internet Protocol (“IP”) address of the computer you are using;
    • The browser used and the operating system you are using;
    • The date and time you access the site;
    • Visitor-specific information such as the pages accessed/visited, the order in which they
         were visited, the time spent on those pages, the hyperlinks employed, and the Internet
         address of the website linked directly to this site.
In addition, we may use third party services such as Google Analytics that collect, monitor and
analyze this information including age, gender and interest categories. This information may be
used to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain
content and better understand online activity.
Cookies
Cookies are files containing small amounts of data, which may include an anonymous unique
identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your computer's
hard drive to facilitate your future access to websites or to enhance data analytics.
2183941_1

Like many sites, we use "cookies" to collect information. You can instruct your browser to
refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept
cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Sites.
We may use “retargeting” services to target Fitchburg State University ads to you when you
visit other websites, based on your prior use of our Sites.
We are the sole owner of the information collected on our Sites and Mobile Apps and we will
not sell or rent this information to third parties, unless specifically disclosed.
Location Information
When you use any mapping features of the Mobile App, we may use GPS technology (or other
similar technology) to determine your current location and display a location map. This
provides real-time location data when using the Mobile App but this data is not stored by the
Mobile App.
If you do not want us to use your location for the purposes set forth above, you should turn
off the location services for the Mobile App, however location-based mapping features of the
Mobile App will be unavailable for use.
What We Do with the Information We Gather
We use this information to understand your needs and analyze the services we provide to you.
In particular, for the following reasons:
     • To answer a question you have asked;
     • To provide you with the information or service you have requested;
     • For internal record keeping;
     • To improve our services, including performance and functionality of the websites; and
     • To periodically send promotional information about University programs, events, or
         other information we think you may find interesting, based upon information or usage
         data you have provided.
Reasons We May Disclose the Information We Gather
We do not disclose confidential information we collect online to individuals or entities
not affiliated with Fitchburg State, except in the limited circumstances described below.
     • We may disclose confidential information pursuant to Fitchburg State policies,
         applicable collective bargaining agreements, and/or state or federal law, including, but
         not limited to, the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”) and the
         Massachusetts Public Records Law.
     • We may be required to disclose confidential information pursuant to a valid court order
         or lawfully issued subpoena, search warrant, or other legal process.
     • We may disclose confidential information to law enforcement if we believe that
         disclosure is necessary to protect the University, to protect the health or safety of
2183941_1

        individuals, or if law enforcement believes that our resources have been used in the
        commission of a crime.
    •   We may disclose confidential information to third parties and University vendors to
        perform services for you or to meet institutional needs.
Note: The above-listed examples are not an exhaustive list.
Security
We are concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your information, including the
information we collect online. We do not allow any non-Fitchburg State entity to collect
information from our network unless those entities obtain written permission from us. We
have put in place industry-standard physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect
information we process and maintain.
Links to Other Websites and Mobile Apps
Fitchburg State’s Sites and Mobile Apps may contain links to third-party websites or apps of
interest. However, once you use these links and leave the Fitchburg State Sites/Mobile Apps,
you should note that we do not have control over other third-party websites/apps. Fitchburg
State is not responsible for the protection and privacy of any information that you provide
while visiting third-party websites/apps and this privacy policy does not govern such sites. You
should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the third-party
websites/apps in question.
Online Surveys and Forms
Fitchburg State employs the use of online surveys and forms on some of the University’s Sites
and Mobile Apps. It is University policy that confidential information gathered in this manner is
used only for the purposes indicated. Unless otherwise noted, your answers are confidential
and individual responses will not be shared with other parties. Non-identifiable aggregate data
may be shared for research and statistical purposes.
Policy Changes
This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason. You are advised to consult
this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes, as continued use is deemed approval of all
changes.
Your Consent
By using our Sites or Mobile Apps, you are consenting to our processing of your information as
set forth in this Privacy Policy now and as amended by us.
Controlling Your Personal Information
If you have any questions regarding privacy while using our Sites or Mobile Apps, or have
questions about our practices, please call the IT Help Desk and submit your request via a service
2183941_1

ticket. They will route the request to the most appropriate department or person to answer the
question.
If You Are Located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”)
If you are located in a member state of the European Union when you receive Fitchburg State
University’s services, you are covered by the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”)
issued by the European Union and applicable to the EEA. Please see our EEA Privacy Provisions
for more information.
2183941_1
